landregistry.gov.uk 2014-07-02

# Privacy statement - Land Registry for England and Wales

Land Registry has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to maintaining the security and confidentiality of personal information. We collect information in order to provide customers and users with a better service and provide a smooth, efficient and personalised experience while using our website, or services. Please note that customers cannot ask us to remove or delete information from the register of title which we are obliged to publish.

## How we use your information

This privacy notice tells you what to expect when Land Registry collects personal information. It applies to information we collect about:

  * visitors to our websites (with the exception of Land Registry's test sites) 
  * people who call our Customer Contact Centre 
  * users of our paper application services ` 
  * users of our services by making paper applications
  * users of our online public services
  * people who use our business e-services
  * job applicants and our current and former employees

### Visitors to our websites 

When someone visits our websites we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting either of our websites. We will not associate any data gathered from the sites with any personally identifying information from any other source. If we do want to collect personally identifying information through our websites, we will be up front about this and say so.

The contact forms on our websites require users to provide certain information – see People who use our forms.

Our online surveys may ask users and customers of our services for contact information (such as an email address). The contact information will be used to contact customers when appropriate. Users may opt out if they choose. 

Please see our [Cookies statement](http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/cookies) for information on our use of cookies..

### People who call our Customer Contact Centre 

When you call our Customer Contact Centre we collect information, such as names and contact details. We use this information to help improve our efficiency and effectiveness. The information is recorded within our various customer systems. Some telephone calls are recorded for quality assurance. We also collect information from customers who want to arrange an appointment to attend one of our Customer Information Centres. The information collected includes names, contact details, title information. For information on our Voice Recording Policy – See [Voice Recording policy](http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/about-us/policy-statements/voice-recording-policy). We will retain telephone recordings for 60 calendar days.

### People who use our forms

Our sites use forms for customers to request information, products and services, give feedback. We may collect contact information such as email addresses and financial information such as bank account details and credit cards numbers. In relation to credit cards, we comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards where applicable. Contact information from the order forms is used to send out orders, customer contact information may be used to get in touch with customers when necessary. Financial information may be used where appropriate to charge for product and services.

### People who use our online public service

Our terms and conditions set out what we may use your information for. You should note that any information we may hold may be disclosed to or shared with others where appropriate. See Disclosure of personal information and Sharing information.

Customers using our Find a property e–service will make payment in advance for services by credit/debit card. In relation to credit and debit cards, we comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards where applicable. When you pay for the services it will be via RBS Worldpay. Card holder information is held by the third party and not Land Registry. Your attention is drawn to the [privacy policy](http://www.rbsworldpay.com/about_us/index.php?page=terms&c=UK)  of RBS Worldpay.

Customers using our free Property Alert service will be able to see day list information for up to ten different title numbers at any given time. They will receive a message sent by email when an application or search is lodged against a title number they have selected. We will disclose details of anyone using the service if a request is made to identify individuals who are searching specific title numbers. 

### People who use our business e-services

For customers using our e-services (including Portal and Business Gateway), we will capture information including details of the enquiry against the records we hold on our Customer Relationship Management system. For all other businesses (including those who have a specified Customer Team) or citizen customers, enquiries may be logged against the business details or generically. We will collect the name and contact details of the person making the enquiry when we have a need to contact them to resolve the enquiry or when there is a need for our Customer Contact Centre to refer the enquiry with Land Registry such as local Land Registry Office.

Our Conditions of Use and the Full Network Access Agreement ** ** sets out how we may use the information collected on businesses and their employees. 

You should note that any information we may hold may be disclosed to or shared with others where appropriate. See Disclosure of personal information and Sharing Information.

### People who make applications

Customers who lodge applications or correspondence with us in connection with a registered title or about the registration of land and properties  are providing us with information. The use of this information is governed by the Land Registration Act 2002 and Land Registration Rules 2003. This includes hold both personal and non-personal information. Official copies of registers of titles and title plans are publicly available upon payment of the prescribed fee. It is also possible to apply for or inspect copies of documents held by Land Registry including scanned electronic images. This information is also publicly available (also upon payment of ther prescribed fee) and governed by section 66 of the Land Registration Act 2002 which sets out the protocol. As the information is made available under this statutory access code, the same information is not available using the Freedom of Information Act 2000.

This information is held indefinitely. The Public Records Act 1958 as amended ordinarily requires that public records selected for permanent preservation are transferred to The National Archives once they are 20 years old. However, this requirement does not apply where the Lord Chancellor has given his approval for their retention by the body holding them. We have obtained an Instrument of Retention in respect of our registers and associated documents, which includes all the associated paperwork, which means we have physical custody of all of those records.

When we handle personal information supplied by you as part of our statutory functions, your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998 are limited. The Data Protection Act 1998 permits us to use personal information for these official purposes. The information is exempt from the disclosure provisions, as it falls within section 34 of that Act. This exempts information that has to be made available to the public under legislation.

In order to maintain the integrity of the register of title we may disclose to or share with others any information we may hold – see Disclosure of personal information and Sharing Information.

### People who make a complaint to us

### 

When we receive a complaint from a person we make up a file containing the details of the complaint. This normally contains the identity of the complainant and any other individuals involved in the complaint.

We will only use the personal information we collect to process the complaint and to check on the level of service we provide. We do compile and publish statistics but not in a form which identifies anyone.

We usually have to disclose the complainant’s identity to whoever the complaint is about. This is inevitable where, for example, the accuracy of a title is in dispute. If a complainant doesn’t want information identifying him or her to be disclosed, we will, in exceptional citcumstances try to respect that but it  will not usually not be possible to handle a complaint on an anonymous basis.

We will keep personal information contained in complaint files in line with our retention policy for a period of 10 years. Our Document Disposal Policy and list is available on request. It will be retained in a secure environment and access to it will be restricted according to the ‘need to know’ principle.

Similarly, where enquiries are submitted to us we will only use the information supplied to us to deal with the enquiry and any subsequent issues and to check on the level of service we provide.

Usually we do not, identify any complainants unless the details have already been made public.

Information from complaint files is not available under Land Registry’s statutory inspection protocol and Open Register. 

#### Usability Suite

Land Registry has a Usability Suite which is used by Land Registry to undertake study/research into product, service and system development. Land Registry’s Usability suite is a facility which hosts a studio where the testing takes place and an observation room where those involved in the development of products or services can observe the testing as it happens. The suite uses world leading eye tracking technology which highlights where users look and shows their immediate reactions and the distribution of their attention during a test.

Usability testing is a way of studying how easy it is to use a product, system or service by testing it with real users. Undertaking this kind of testing will help Land Registry to develop new, and refresh existing, products and service as we move to more digital services. 

Customers and staff may be asked to participate in such research. This is purely voluntary and participants have the right to withdraw at any time. Participants in such studies will be given information about the research being undertaken and we will be asked to give their consent before taking part. The informed consents are held securely. The information obtained from the research project will be held for no longer than the information has a useful value.

For further information you should contact Gavin Thorne, Head of Customer and Market Insight Team: [gavin.thorne@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk](mailto:gavin.thorne@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk)

### People who use our other services

Land Registry offers various services to the public. For example, we send out public guides and other publications. We may use a third party to deal with some services.

We have to hold the details of those who have requested  any particular service in order to provide it. However, we only use these details to provide the service requested and for other related purposes. For example, we might use information about people who have requested a publication to carry out a survey to find out if they are happy with the level of service they received. 

### Job applicants, current and former employees

When individuals apply to work at Land Registry we will only use the information they supply to us to process their application and to monitor recruitment statistics. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference,we will not do so without informing them beforehand unless the disclosure is required by law. 

Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 24 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted. We retain de-personalised statistical information about applicants to help inform our recruitment activities, but no individuals are identifiable from that data.

Once a person has taken up employment with Land Registry, we will compile a file relating to their employment. Our Staff Information Charter sets out what we do.

### Complaints or queries

Land Registry tries to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is inaccurate, unfair or misleading. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures.

This privacy notice was drafted primarily with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of Land Registry’s collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Any requests for this should be sent to the address below.

### Access to personal information

Land Registry tries to be as open as it can be in terms of giving people access to their personal information. Individuals can find out if we hold any personal information by making a ‘subject access request’ under the Data Protection Act 1998. If we do hold information about you we will:

  * give you a description of it; 
  * tell you why we are holding it; 
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and 
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

For further information see [DPA page on website](http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/information/data-protection). You should note that there are exceptions under the Data Protection Act 1998 and if these apply, we may not necessarily provide you with information requested.

If we do hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes by, once again, contacting the Data Protection Officer.

### Your choices 

Land Registry seeks to ensure that your information and preferences are accurate and complete. If you wish to view, change your information or opt out of receiving information from us, please let us know by sending your name, full address, email address and company name (if applicable) either:

  * by email to [privacy@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk](mailto:privacy@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk)
  * or write to us at FREEPOST RSZE - TEZA - JCTH, Land Registry, CRM Team, Land Registry Croydon Office, Trafalgar House, 1 Bedford Park, Croydon, CR0 2AQ.  

**Please note that you cannot use this to ask us to make changes to the register of title for example, by the removal of price paid information in the register.**

### 

### Disclosure of personal information

In many circumstances we will not disclose or use personal data without consent. However there will be occasions when we will need to disclose or share or otherwise use personal information within our own internal departments and/or with other government departments and agencies, law enforcement and regulatory agencies and other relevant bodies. Examples of such occasions are when we investigate a land registration matter or complaint or to prevent and detect crime.

Our Information Charter sets out the standards that you can expect from us. [See Information Charter.](http://www.landregistry.gov.uk/public/information/information-charter)

You can also get further information by contacting The Data Protection Officer  \- See details below. 

### Freedom of Information

You should note that we are under a duty to comply with the Freedom of Information Act 2000 and the Environmental Information Regulations 2004. We may disclose information in order to comply with any legislation including the Freedom of Information Act 2000 and Environmental Information Regulations 2004 or an order of court, without obtaining your consent so that we can comply with any applicable information disclosure requirements. 

### Sharing of Information

Land Registry may, where appropriate, share any information held with third parties such as other government departments, law enforcement and regulatory agencies and other relevant bodies, (including Specified Anti – Fraud Organisations under section 68 Serious Crime Act 2007, counter fraud department, and counter fraud organisations and their members)  if false or inaccurate information is provided and/or if the sharing of information is considered to be:

  * in the public interest , for example, investigation of land banking schemes and/or 
  * for the prevention and detection of crime including prevention, detection and investigation of registration fraud,

Information disclosed to counter fraud organisations may be accessed and used by us and other organisations to prevent fraud and money laundering. Further details explaining how such information held by counter fraud organisations may be used can be obtained from our Data Protection Officer using the contact details set out at the end of this notice.

Information that relates to confirmed fraud will be routinely shared with the Police for one or more of the following policing purposes:

  * Protecting life and property 
  * Preserving order 
  * Preventing the commission of offences 
  * Bringing offenders to justice 
  * Any duty or responsibility of the police arising from common or statute law. 

We follow the Information Commissioner’s Data Sharing Code of Practice so far as practicable. There may be occasions when we may share information on a limited basis in order to assess whether data sharing on a formal basis is beneficial for these purposes. 

### Protecting your information

We acknowledge that your trust and are committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain accuracy and ensure proper use of information, we have physical, electronic and managerial processes to safeguard and secure the information we collect.

### Security

We have security measures in place on our sites and services to protect against loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. We will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal information, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not secure and for this reasons we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any information in transit from or to you. Therefore, information sent over the internet via e-mail from our website may not be as secure as information that you provide us with to register for our services. 

### Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. 

### Changes to this privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review.

### How to contact us

Requests for information about our privacy policy can be emailed to our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:dataprotection@landregistry.gsi.gov.uk) or by writing to:

The Data Protection Officer  
Land Registry  
Trafalgar House  
1 Bedford Park  
Croydon  
CR0 2AQ
